Connecticut Soldiers Collection
© 2008 University of Connecticut
Connecticut Soldiers Collection, Davis Family Correspondence.
1938-1945.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center.
Davis, Rodney O.
Davis, Dewey.
.5 linear feet.
Collection contains letters to Carl and Lil Davis from their sons and relatives during World War II.
MSS20070039
Biography
Lil and Carl Davis lived in Hartford, CT, during World War II, and the collection consists of the letters they received from their sons, Rodney O. and Dewey, who were in the armed forces during the war. More is known of Rod, who enlisted in 1942 in the Navy, and served in the Atlantic and Pacific until he was discharged in 1945. He was a radio operator on the USS Hermitage. The collection also contains letters from nephews and friends serving in the war.
Scope and Content
The collection contains correspondence addressed to Lil and Carl Davis of Hartford, Connecticut, during World War II from family members serving abroad. Some of the letters included photographs which are also included in the collection.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by correspondent and chronologically therein.
Series I: Correspondence ( 1938-1945 )
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Davis, Rodney O.--Correspondence.; Davis, Dewey--Correspondence.
Subjects:
Soldiers--Connecitucut--Correspondence.; World War, 1939-1945--Connecitucut--Personal narratives.; Soldiers' writings, American.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Photographs.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was purchased in 2007.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Correspondence, 1938-1945
  - Rodney O. Davis
    - 1942 January - April (Box 1:, Folder 1)
    - 1942 May - December (Box 1:, Folder 2)
    - 1943 January - March (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - 1943 April - June (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - 1943 July 1-18 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - 1943 July 18-31 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - 1943 August - September (Box 1:, Folder 7)
    - 1943 October (Box 1:, Folder 8)
    - 1943 November - December (Box 1:, Folder 9)
    - 1944 January - February (Box 2:, Folder 10)
    - 1944 April - December (Box 2:, Folder 11)
    - 1945 January - May (Box 2:, Folder 12)
    - 1945 June - November (Box 2:, Folder 13)
  - Dewey Davis
    - 1942-1945 (Box 2:, Folder 14)
  - General correspondence
    - 1938-1944 (Box 2:, Folder 15)
  - Photographs
    - undated, 1942 (Box 2:, Folder 16)